<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Running on LinuxUK</title>
    <link>/tags/running/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Running on LinuxUK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Jamie Bennett</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 20:44:42 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/running/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheddar Half Marathon and Broadlands 10 Miler</title>
      <link>/post/cheddar_half_and_broadlands_10miler/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 20:44:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cheddar_half_and_broadlands_10miler/</guid>
      <description>A bit belated but here is a short report of two events I ran over the last month or so: the Keynsham 10 Miler and the Cheddar Gorge Half Marathon.
Keynsham 10 Miler (10 miles, 16.1 km) This event was held on Sunday 22nd May in, you guessed it, Keynsham. The weather was fine although it had been raining the previous days which mean the largely undulating and off-road run was, muddy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pensford 10k</title>
      <link>/post/pensford10k/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 21:13:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/pensford10k/</guid>
      <description>Another week, another race, this time the Pensford 10k event, but lets take a little step back first.
At the beginning of my &amp;lsquo;racing&amp;rsquo; (very loose term for official events) calendar selection I had the aim of adding at least one, preferably two events per month to ensure that the pressure to line up against others kept me honest and provided the motivation to get my backside off the couch and training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running the Cheddar Gorge 10k</title>
      <link>/post/cheddar_gorge_10k/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 20:11:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cheddar_gorge_10k/</guid>
      <description>This week I ran the 2016 inaugural Cheddar Gorge Challenge event, the 10k race. Billed as a &amp;lsquo;lumpy course&amp;rsquo; these series of runs offer &amp;ldquo;more climbing just getting to the start than you will in most other events&amp;rdquo;. With the affectionately named Hell Steps towards the end this is a tough run but more importantly, it is a fun event. Cheddar is beautiful, steeped in history and picturesque from the bottom of the gorge let alone from running up and down it so the prospect of completing 3 races (10k, half marathon, and marathon) in and around the area was too enticing to pass up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running in Nepal</title>
      <link>/post/running_in_nepal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 17:58:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/running_in_nepal/</guid>
      <description>Nepal is such a wonderful place. Steeped in history and culture with some of the most breath-taking sights to be seen, Nepal is the home to Buddhism, the Himalayas, and of course the mighty Mt Everest. Despite all this wealth, the country and the people themselves face a lot of challenges. Economically Nepal is considered a third-world country with many people in utter poverty. To compound this hardship, Nepal has also experienced terrible earthquakes that have left many dead and even more without basic needs such as accommodation, access to food and clean water, and education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parkrun</title>
      <link>/post/parkrun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 14:03:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/parkrun/</guid>
      <description>I have a confession to make. While I have publicly supported the parkrun initiative for some time and I wholeheartedly believe it is a great idea, I have never actually ran one myself. There have been many excuses from family conflicts at the weekends to blaming the weather but this week I thought I would actually ignore all of this and partake in the spectacle. I chose the closest event, which for me was Southwick Country Park in Trowbridge and arrived before the customary 9am start time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>