<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on LinuxUK</title>
    <link>www.linuxuk.org/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on LinuxUK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Jamie Bennett</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 10:18:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="www.linuxuk.org/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting back into blogging</title>
      <link>www.linuxuk.org/post/more-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 10:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.linuxuk.org/post/more-blogging/</guid>
      <description>Its been a while, in fact it has been around a year since I updated this site (to be fair I did write a few posts on another blog during that period &amp;hellip; excuses, excuses) which I attribute to a increasingly busy schedule but more to a lack of enthusiasm. So, in an attempt to get back into this blogging lark I thought it would be a good opportunity to redesign the site with Hugo, a static, but more importantly Markdown-based web engine, and put up a few articles on something dear to my heart, Software Engineering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writings</title>
      <link>www.linuxuk.org/writings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 15:58:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.linuxuk.org/writings/</guid>
      <description>In addition to this website, I often write for other online and offline publications, some of which can be found below.
 Sustainability Journal: Heathcare in the Smart Home: A study of past, present, and future Info Security: Securing Against Developer Pressure Information Security Buzz: IoT Code of Conduct IT Pro Portal: New business models on their way for IoT hardware Electronics Weekly: New business models on IoT hardware, by software Tech Radar: How 5G will enable the next generation of IoT deployments New Electronics: Industry 4.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>