<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>robotics on LinuxUK</title>
    <link>/tags/robotics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in robotics on LinuxUK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Jamie Bennett</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 10:37:08 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/robotics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deprecating software is hard; why the move to ROS 2 is causing heated debate</title>
      <link>/post/deprecating_software_is_hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 10:37:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/deprecating_software_is_hard/</guid>
      <description>Software never stays the same Inevitably, all software is destined to die. Whether that is through becoming end of life (EOL), obsolete, or unused, or through the code being rewritten and replaced, software is not static and nor should it be. Bug fixes, security updates, and new functionality ensure that code churn, or the number of lines being modified, keeps developers busy and projects healthy. But, what happens when software completely changes?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Computer Interaction, to the max</title>
      <link>/post/hci-to-the-max/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 18:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hci-to-the-max/</guid>
      <description>Interfacing with computers is inevitable in today&amp;rsquo;s developed societies but what most people think of when asked about computer interaction is probably bashing the keyboard, one finger at a time, on a laptop or desktop or, for the more tech-savvy they may talk about phones and tablets. Less people talk about cars, TVs, airport ticketing machines, wearables, digital assistants like Alexa or Siri, even fridges, washing machines, and billboards. A small but increasingly vocal subset talk about a new generation of computing that will revolutionise the definition of computers and even humanity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>